ABOUT ME

Creative full stack developer looking to grow with a dedicated team. Enthusiastic to learn, spending my free time reading up on libraries and techniques. I am obsessed with surmounting engineering hurdles and hunting down pesky bugs. Over 5 years experience working in IT.

AWARDS & PUBS.

Airman of the Year - 961st AACS, Kadena AB, 2010

Journal Publication -

Jackson, E. D.; Green, S. C.; Prieto, A. L. Electrochemical Performance of Electrodeposited Zn4Sb3Films for Sodium-Ion Secondary Battery Anodes. ACS Applied Materials & Interfaces 2015, 7 (14), 7447–7450.

SKILLS

Languages:

React, Node.js HTML, CSS, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Python

Operating Systems:

Linux (Arch/Antergos), MS Windows

DevOps:

Git

IDEs/Text Editors:

VSCode, nVim

Misc:

Agile methodology

CONTACT



scott96707@gmail.com



(970) 231-4985



/scott96707



in/scott96707

ScottGreen

Full Stack Developer | Denver, CO

PROJECTS

Stock Grapher App (work in progress)

React - D3 - JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Display stock information with D3 and React. Pulls market information from IEX ΔPI

Face Recognition App

React - Node.js - Express.js - PostgreSQL - JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Register and login users to a PostreSQL database, input the URL of a photograph, and any human faces in the picture will be outlined with a border. Uses the free Clarifai API to identify faces in the photograph. Hosted w/ Heroku: https://facerecognitionfrontend.herokuapp.com/

Star Wars App

React - JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Responsive front-end displaying information which is retrieved from a free Star Wars API and displayed on individual cards. Cards are interactive.

WORK HISTORY

(Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2018)

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - T4S Partners

- Used a declarative scripting language to design multiple back-end systems, including an auto-assignment ticketing system, REST API integration, and email parsing.
- Pair programmed in an end-to-end development pipeline, with Dev., Test and Prod. servers. Coordinated testing, deployment of features, and bug fixes for a SaaS business product.
- Troubleshot production-affecting service outages. Determined causes and implemented solutions, minimizing downtime and improving client relations.

(June 2008 - June 2012)

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN - USAF | Kadena, Japan and Beale, CA

 Operated in teams composed of varied specialties to maintain two AWACS aircraft and a DCGS system.

EDUCATION

(May, 2016)

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, CHEMISTRY - Colorado State University

- Organized study groups for advanced chemistry courses. Helped improve classmate's grades from C's to A's.
- ACS certified degree with courses in organic, inorganic and physical chemistry, biochemistry, calculus-based statistics and physics.

(Sep. 2016 - August 2017)

MATERIALS SCIENCE ENGINEERING - University of Washington

Advanced coursework in semiconductor theory and design.